Guide to the Julian and Juliette Huxley papers, 1899-1988 MS 512
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Julian and Juliette Huxley papers
1899-1988
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Huxley, Julian, 1887-1975
MS 512
21 Linear Feet (41 boxes)
Journals, scrapbooks, sketches, and photographs by and about Julian and Juliette Huxley, covering family life; travels on behalf of UNESCO and for other research and personal purposes to Africa, Australia, and Europe; awards and honors; and academic and creative writing.
Biographical Note
Julian Sorell Huxley, the grandson of Thomas Henry Huxley and great-nephew of Matthew Arnold, was born June 22, 1887. The union of the Huxley and Arnold families brought about a happy combination of what Julian's younger brother Aldous would call "blue genes", but the combined family traditions also imposed an obligation of intellectual excellence and social responsibility. This obligation was keenly felt by Julian Huxley from an early age. It was enhanced by his affinity for the interests which had earned his grandfather his place in the history of science, and thus, it soon became apparent that young Julian would be Thomas Huxley's intellectual heir as well as his grandson. This inheritance would prove both a joy and a burden, for while Julian Huxley achieved great renown as a scientist and popularizer of science, he was plagued, like his grandfather, by serious and debilitating attacks of depression. In spite of this he was able, throughout a long career, to contribute significantly to the fields of ethology, ecology and cancer research, and to act effectively as a powerful proponent of neo-Darwinism.
He was educated at Eton and Oxford, where he followed his own inclinations and his grandfather's example by studying Natural Science. His scientific interests were combined with literary talents which were officially recognized in 1908, when he was awarded the Newdigate Prize for English Verse at Oxford, an honor which he remembered with pride even after a lifetime of honors and accomplishments. (It is note-worthy and characteristic that he spent his prize money on a microscope.)
After completing his schooling, he began his career at the institution which had taught him: in 1910, he became a lecturer in Zoology at Oxford. Two years later, however, he departed from the course traditional to a young man of his academic interests and social background. He left England and Oxford to accept a position as Research Associate at the newly established Rice Institute in Houston, Texas, and by 1913 he had become Assistant Professor of Biology there. He remained in Houston until 1916 when he returned to Europe to take part in World War I.
After serving as an army intelligence officer in Italy, he came home to marry and to take up a position as Senior Demonstrator in Zoology at Oxford. From 1919 to 1925 he remained at Oxford, carrying out his famous axolotl experiments and participating in the university's expedition to Spitsbergen. In 1925 he became Professor of Zoology at King's College, University of London. But he did not remain long in that position. The following year he made a decision which, like his decision to teach at the Rice Institute, would move him away from the path followed by most of his fellow scientists. He accepted the invitation of H.G. Wells to collaborate on what would become The Science of Life, and in 1927 resigned his position at King's College. This meant a new direction for his career, for although he was Fullerian Professor of Physiology in the Royal Institution from 1927 to 1929, after that he held no academic position. For ten years he was a private person working to advance his ideas about the biological sciences not as a researcher nor as a teacher, but as a writer on scientific developments and their relationship to contemporary social issues.
In 1935 he accepted the position of Secretary of the Zoological Society of London. In this capacity he had the means to encourage solid research on animal behavior while introducing innovative methods for implementing his vision of the zoo as an educational institution. Unfortunately his leadership aroused the displeasure of some members of the Society, and in 1942 he resigned under pressure. He continued, however, his work as a writer and lecturer and was known throughout war-time Britain for his participation as a panel member of the BBC Brains Trust program.
The end of the war brought an opportunity for him to put many of his cherished ideals and projects into practice. True to family tradition, he had always viewed science, art and literature as part of a great whole. Thus when he became a member of the commission formed to plan what would become Unesco, he ensured that science would be an integral part of the educational and cultural institution. When in 1946 he became Unesco's first Director-General, he set out a program cosmopolitan in vision, one concerned with mankind in relationship with nature and with its past, one in which art and science were equally valued. He even went so far as to advocate his own solution to the troubling questions of modern society, his "religion" of scientific humanism, as an official basis for Unesco's philosophy. This he himself came later to find unwise. During his tenure as Director-General he also began to articulate fully the concerns which would occupy the later years of his life: the relation of overpopulation to poverty and ignorance, the necessity for the conservation of wilderness and wildlife, and the importance of the renunciation of parochial views on religion and politics. Finally, he came to stress even more strongly than before his optimistic belief that mankind can and should take control of its own environmental and biological destiny.
In 1948 his term of office with Unesco came to an end and Huxley was once again a private citizen. The remainder of his life was spent traveling, lecturing and writing in support of the causes to which he was devoted: evolutionary theory and its significance for potential human development, ecology and the preservation of wildlife and population control. He was honored often for his contributions to science and to society, receiving prizes and awards for his efforts in helping the general public to better understand contemporary scientific thought. In 1958 he received a knighthood. In 1965, in a culmination of work he began in his youth with his field studies of the behavior of the great crested grebe, he organized a Royal Society Symposium on the Ritualization of Behavior in Animals and Man, and in 1970 he received the International Union for the Conservation of Nature Gold Medal for outstanding contributions to scientific research related to conservation.
On February 14, 1975, at the age of 87, Sir Julian Huxley died. His life had been long, beginning in the Victorian era and ending in a world which his grandfather could scarcely have imagined. He served many of the causes with which the 20th century will no doubt become identified, and his influence on the development of contemporary biological science was considerable. Through his field studies of animal behavior and his synthetic approach to Darwinian evolutionary theory and Mendelian genetics, he helped determine the direction of modern biology. As an educator his influence was incalculable, for he taught not only such men as E.B. Ford and A.C. Hardy, but through his writings, perhaps millions of men and women as well. He was, moreover, known for his encouragement of aspiring scientists and scholars. In his catholic interests, in his belief in the interrelationship of science and arts, he extended his influence beyond the laboratory of the classroom and reached artists, writers, musicians, politicians and finally the general public. Such interests and such influence indicate that his desire to be known as one to whom "nothing human and nothing in external nature was alien" was fulfilled.
Juliette Huxley: Lady Marie Juliette Baillot was born in Auvernier, Switzerland, in a village near Lake Neuchâtel, on December 6, 1896, and moved to England at the age of nineteen to work as a French teacher for Ottoline Morrell. At Garsington, Morrell's home, she met numerous guests including Aldous Leonard Huxley (ALH) and Julian Huxley. Julian and Juliette began courting in 1916, and corresponded throughout 1917 and 1918 while Julian served in the Army Service Corps and Army Intelligence during World War I. The two were married in 1919. Their first son, Anthony, was born in 1920, and their second, Francis, in 1923. Juliette followed Julian in his tenures at King's College and the Royal Institute in London during the 1920s and until 1931, when Julian resigned. During Julian's term as Secretary of the Zoological Society of London from 1935 until 1942, Juliette loved living in their home at the London Zoo. She enjoyed walking among the animals and hearing them at night. In 1946 the couple moved to Paris while Julian Huxley served as Director-General of UNESCO.
Juliette Huxley traveled extensively with her husband throughout the 1950s and early 1960s. She later published Wild Lives of Africa (1963), which was based on her experiences traveling with Julian during 1960 and 1961. The two eventually returned to London, where Julian died in 1975. Juliette Huxley continued living in London, surrounded by her own sculptures and the artwork of their numerous friends from over the years. She continued writing as well, publishing her autobiography Leaves of the Tulip Tree in 1986. She also continued to take notice of advancements in the fields in which her husband was interested, including biology, conservation, humanism, and social evolution. Juliette Huxley's brother-in-law (and Nobel Prize winner), Aldous Huxley and her two sons, among other life-long acquaintances, frequently visited her. Her son Anthony died in 1992, which affected her own health. Juliette Huxley died on September 28, 1994.
Scope and Contents
Journals, scrapbooks, sketches, and photographs by and about Julian and Juliette Huxley, covering family life; travels on behalf of UNESCO and for other research and personal purposes to Africa, Australia, and Europe; awards and honors; and academic and creative writing.
Conditions Governing Access
This material is open for research.
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
General Note
Portions of this collection are available online at: https://scholarship.rice.edu/handle/1911/77464
Index Terms
Subjects
Biology; Environment
Document Types
clippings (information artifacts); photographs; scrapbooks; Audiocassettes; diaries; awards
Subjects (Persons)
Huxley, Juliette, 1896-1994
Subjects (Corporations)
Zoological Society of London.; Unesco.
- Series I: Journals & Scrapbooks, 1908-1988, 242957
  - Subseries A: Journals, 242964
    Scope and Contents note
    Of the forty-five journals total, the majority were written by Juliette Huxley. The 1929 journal (not Africa) also has writings from 1933, 1937, 1939, 1975, and the one from 1942-43 also has inscriptions for 1964 and 1988. There is one journal from Julian Huxley, dated October-November 1908. There is also one journal, dated 1975, with a couple of notations by an apparent at-home nurse, perhaps during one of Juliette Huxley's illnesses. The journals are filed chronologically.
    - 1908, 1927, 1929 (Africa), 1929, 1932 (MJH's trip to Baghdad), 1939 (Mostly war & Zoo crisis), 1942-43, 1947 (2 – both UNESCO – one from various spots in Europe, the other from Paris), 1947-48 (UNESCO), 1948, 1954, 1954-55, 1954-58, 1956, 1957, 242966 (Box 1, Folder -)
    - 1958-59, 1959-61, 1960 (Africa), 1960, 1961, 1961 (2 – both Ghana & Nigeria), 1963, 1964 (Los Angeles), 1964-65, 1965 (Africa), 1966 (2 – both JSH's breakdown), 1967-69, 1969-71, 1969-74, 1971 (Nairobi), 1971-72, 1972-73, 1973-74, 1974-75, 1975 (nurse notes), 1975-76, 1977-79, 1979-81, 1981-83, 1984-85, 242965 (Box 2, Folder -)
  - Subseries B: Scrapbooks, 242960
    - Scrapbook 1: newsclippings and article excerpts about and photographs of Julian and Juliette Huxley and Huxley friends such as Yehudi Menuhin, Avraham Yoffe, D. H. Lawrence, and Bertrand Russell. Of particular interest are a photograph of Julian Huxley at Eton and one of him in uniform during World War I., 242963 (Box 3, Folder -)
    - Scrapbook 2: large, red scrapbook containing mostly material related to art, sculpture, and structures, perhaps collected throughout the Huxleys many overseas travels., 242962 (Box 4, Folder -)
    - Scrapbook 3: brown scrapbook with "J.S.H." on the cover contains a tribute to Julian Huxley from UNESCO., 242961 (Box 4, Folder -)
  - Subseries C: Tribute to JSH, 1975, 242958
    - Two bound volumes of letters and personal reminisces of Julian Huxley compiled for "A Day of Tribute to Sir Julian Huxley," held in June 1975, several months after Huxley's death., 242959 (Box 5, Folder -)
- Series II: Works by JSH, 1907-1959, 242946
  JSH's academic writings, sketches, notes, novel typescript, and the poem that garnered him the Newdigate Prize for English Verse make up this series. The series is filed alphabetically with the academic writings being filed chronologically.
  - Academic papers, 1910-22, 242956 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Academic papers, 1923-26, 242955 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Academic papers, 1927-31, 242954 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Academic papers, 1932-40, 242953 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Academic papers, 1941-59, 242952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Newdigate Poem, 1907, 242951 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Notes, 242950 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Notes for Lectures, 242949 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Novel, 242948 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sketches & Sketchbooks, 242947 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Series III: Photos & Negatives, 1899-1984, 242565
  This series contains photographs of the Huxley and Baillot families, as well as photographs of friends, places, structures, and wildlife. There are 3 subseries within this series: Albums, Loose Photographs, and Negatives. Within the Loose Photographs subseries appear to be 9 sub-subseries: JSH; JSH & MJH; Family; Friends; Places (or Travel); Wildlife; Artistic; Structures; and Oversize. Many of the Travel photographs appear to have been taken in connection with Huxley's association with UNESCO.
  The first 4 boxes in this Series consist of 28 photo albums. Many of the Albums were given numbers by the creator or donor. There are Albums 101-105 and 1-22 (with #s 2, 4, 5, 12, and 18 missing, and two # 13's). All of the photographs in Albums 20, 21, and 22 are loose. Many of those in Album 1, Album 10 and Album 101 have lost their glue. Album 101 also contains a table of contents on the first page. Albums 3 and 9 have packages of negatives in the front. The albums have been arranged chronologically.
  JSH, MJH, other Huxleys, Baillots, and Huxley friends are included in at least two of the packages of miscellaneous negatives in Box 17, one of those in Box 18, and one of those in Box 20.
  - Subseries A: Albums, 1899-1904, 242917
    - 1899-1937 (Album 3), 242945 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - 1900-1908 (Album 101), 242944 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - 1900-1901, 242943 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - 1902-1924 (Album 1 – 2 cartes, Oxford, Ischia, Naples, U.K., Texas, K.F., Early Sibs), 242942 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - c. 1903, 1905, 1910 (Album 103), 242941 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - 1908 (JSH, Album 102), 242940 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - 1912-16, U.S.A. (Album 105, Texas) [Labeled Texas but the photographs appear to be of Colorado and/or the West.), 242939 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - 1925-1930, 242938 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - c. 1932 (Album 9, MJH Baghdad, F[reya] Stark), 242937 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - 1934, Bel Alp (1/2), 242936 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - 1934, Bel Alp (Album 7) (2/2), 242935 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - 1936, Spain (Album 13, MJH & Dora M.), 242934 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - 1937-1943 (Album 14, Whipsnade Camp Logbook), 242933 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1945 (Album 15, Auversier?), 242932 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 1945-49, UNESCO, 242931 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1947 (Album 16, UNESCO—Lebanon), 242930 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1947 (Album 17), 242929 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1947-48, Mexico (Album 10), 242928 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1948 (Album 13), 242927 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - c. 1963 (Album 8), 242926 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - 1965 (Album 11), 242925 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - 1965, Israel (Album 19), 242924 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - 1969-1971 (Album 20), 242923 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - 1973-1975 (Album 21), 242922 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - c. 1983-1984 (Album 22), 242921 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - n.d. (Album 104) [It appears to be c. 1900ish) [probably c. 1905 since Album 103 is 1905 and Album 105 is 1912], 242920 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - n.d., Ireland & Switzerland (Album 6) [probably c. 1934 since Album 7 is 1934], 242919 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - n.d., Yugoslavia, 242918 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: Loose Photographs, 242625
    - Sub-Subseries 1: JSH, 1920-1979 (2 Boxes), 242894
      - 1920s, 242916 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - 1930s, 242915 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - 1940s, 242914 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - 1950s, 242913 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - 1960s, 242912 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - 1970s, 242911 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - n.d., 242910 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - At home, 242909 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - At school, 242908 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - At zoo, 242907 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - Caricatures, 242906 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Death, 242905 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Hands, 242904 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Military, 242903 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Negatives, 242902 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Relaxing, 242901 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - UNESCO, 242900 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Used in Memorial, 242899 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Julian Huxley with Others (including H. G. Wells, May Sarton, Avraham Yoffe, Dorothy Elmhirst, Edith Russell, Prince Philip of England, Cyrus Eaton, and Kenneth Clark), 242898 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Working, 242897 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Young man, 242896 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Youth, 242895 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Sub-Subseries 2: JSH/JSH & MJH, n.d. (1 Box), 242889
      - Julian & Juliette Huxley, 242893 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Julian & Juliette Huxley with others (including Yigael Yadin), 242892 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Juliette Huxley, 242891 (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Juliette Huxley with others (including David Attenborough, George Darwin, Samuel S. Koteliansky, and Sir Edmund Hillary), 242890 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Sub-Subseries 3: Family (2 Boxes), 242867
      - Arnold Family, 242888 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Baillot Family, 242887 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Collier Family, 242886 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Great-grandchildren, 242885 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Huxley, Aldous, 242884 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Huxley, Anthony, 242883 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Huxley, David, 242882 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Huxley, Francis, 242881 (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Huxley, Henrietta, 242880 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Huxley, Julia, 242879 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Huxley, Leonard, 242878 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Huxley, Maria, 242877 (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Huxley, Margaret, 242876 (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Huxley, Matthew, 242875 (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Huxley, Thomas H., 242874 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - Huxley, Trev., 242873 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - Huxley, Zoe, 242872 (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - Huxley family, 242871 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - Huxley family groups, 242870 (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Huxley family negatives, 242869 (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Ward Family, 242868 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Sub-Subseries 4: Friends (1 Box), 242821
      - Adamson, Joy, 242866 (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Best, Alan, 242865 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Black, Lesley, 242864 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Brandt, Bob, 242863 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Bronowski, Jacob, 242862 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Brooke, Leonora (of Sarawak [a region of Borneo]), 242861 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Darwin, George, 242860 (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Davidson, Jo, 242859 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Eton Classmates, 242858 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Fisher, James, 242857 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Fordham, Kathleen, 242856 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Friends, Names Unknown, 242855 (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Gielgud, Mimi, 242854 (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Goldschmidt, Tex, 242853 (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Hammersley, Violet, 242852 (Box 17, Folder 15)
      - Hardy, Alister, 242851 (Box 17, Folder 16)
      - Hogben, Lancelot, 242850 (Box 17, Folder 17)
      - Koteliansky, Samuel, 242849 (Box 17, Folder 18)
      - Kuenzel, Ricarda, 242848 (Box 17, Folder 19)
      - Lawrence, D. H., 242847 (Box 17, Folder 20)
      - Lockley, Ronald, 242846 (Box 17, Folder 21)
      - Loos, Anita, 242845 (Box 17, Folder 22)
      - Marconi Staff, 242844 (Box 17, Folder 23)
      - Middleton, Dora, 242843 (Box 17, Folder 24)
      - Misc. Friends, 242842 (Box 17, Folder 25)
      - Mitchison, Naomi, 242841 (Box 17, Folder 26)
      - Moore, Henry, 242840 (Box 17, Folder 27)
      - Morrell, Julian, 242839 (Box 17, Folder 28)
      - Morrell, Ottoline, 242838 (Box 17, Folder 29)
      - Mountfort, Guy, 242837 (Box 17, Folder 30)
      - Muller, Herman, 242836 (Box 17, Folder 31)
      - Museum Darwinianum, 242835 (Box 17, Folder 32)
      - Negatives, 242834 (Box 17, Folder 33)
      - Nichols, Robert, 242833 (Box 17, Folder 34)
      - Priestley, J. B., 242832 (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - Rensch, Bernard, 242831 (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - Russell, Bertrand, 242830 (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Sarton, May, 242829 (Box 17, Folder 38)
      - Spender, Stephen, 242828 (Box 17, Folder 39)
      - Unknown, 242827 (Box 17, Folder 40)
      - Unknown, at Garsington, 242826 (Box 17, Folder 41)
      - Wells, H. G., 242825 (Box 17, Folder 42)
      - Wendel, Beth, 242824 (Box 17, Folder 43)
      - Wooley, Leonard, 242823 (Box 17, Folder 44)
      - 45 World Health Organization, 242822 (Box 17, Folder 45)
    - Sub-Subseries 5: Places (or Travel), ca. 1932-1984, 242636
      - Callander (Ontario? Scotland?), 242820 (Box 17, Folder 46)
      - Garsington, 242819 (Box 17, Folder 47)
      - Africa, 242818 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Africa, Negatives, 242817 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Artwork, 242816 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Ceylon, 242815 (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Croatia, 242814 (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Egypt, 242813 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - France, 242812 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Guatemala (includes envelopes which were found empty), 242811 (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Indonesia, 242810 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Italy, 242809 (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Lebanon, 242808 (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Lebanon, negatives, 242807 (Box 18, Folder 12)
      - Mexico, 242806 (Box 18, Folder 13)
      - Mexico, 1945, 242805 (Box 18, Folder 14)
      - Misc. Negatives, 242804 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      - Nigeria, 242803 (Box 18, Folder 16)
      - Oregon, Apr. 1962 (Georgia Pacific), 242802 (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Oregon, Apr. 1962, Slides (Georgia Pacific), 242801 (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Pugwash, 242800 (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Russia, 242799 (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Spain, 242798 (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Thailand, 242797 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Travel Notebook, 1962, 1963 (Switzerland, Uganda, Ethiopia), 242796 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Travel Notebook, Negatives, 242795 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - USSR, 1932, 242794 (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - USSR, 1932, Negatives, 242793 (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - Unknown, 242792 (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
      - 1937, Mid-Summer, 242791 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - Africa, 242790 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - Africa, 1944, 242789 (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - Africa (Duplicates), 242788 (Box 20, Folder 4)